# GIOACCHINO DI NARDO

+44 (0) 747 391 3467 | gioacchino.dinardo@gmail.com | GitHub | Blog | Website | LinkedIn

#### **Profile**

Full Stack Software Developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks, HTML, CSS, WordPress, and a background in legal and banking sectors. I enjoy dealing with complex and original ideas while working with likeminded people in a creative and stimulating environment. Above all, I am passionate about programming and learning new tools. When not coding, I enjoy connecting with people and exploring the surroundings with my camera.

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## Lawyered - GitHub | Demo

A platform that allows users to find suitable lawyers for their needs

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for clients, lawyers, and appointments
- Utilised REST architecture and PostgresSQL to populate and maintain data for both lawyers and clients
- Implemented user interface employing React with Material UI, Semantic UI, and vanilla CSS
- Employed JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

### Jolie – GitHub | Demo

An e-commerce marketplace that allows users to browse hundreds of items and shop for clothes and accessories

- Built Rails API backend, allowing admins to manage their stores and customers to manage their baskets via RESTful architecture and CRUD operations
- Designed user interface by using React, Bootstrap, CSS

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Nodejs, Sinatra, APIs, Capybara, RSpec, MVC design, REST architecture, Postgres, MongoDB, SQL, JSON, git CSS, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Material UI, HTML, WordPress

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Feb 2018 – Feb 2019 Business Analyst at Barclays Bank UK – London

- I supported clients with their day-to-day transactions, matching their needs with Barclays' main financial services such as transferring funds, exchanging currencies, borrowing capital, and so on
- I enhanced my social intelligence by developing real relationships with customers, premier and business clients in order to gain their trust and confidence and to get a clear picture of their individual needs

Jun 2017 – Apr 2018 NovoVape Ltd, CEO & Co-founder – London

- I co-founded NovoVape Ltd, an e-commerce provider of e-cigarettes, opening in Italy and in the UK
- I created the website, dealing with design and web development. I was able to work on my own as well as leading teams of experts on the matter while dealing with both suppliers and customers
- I drafted NovoVape's business plan and contributed to its USP, executive summary, market strategy and cash-flow

Feb 2017 – Mar 2017 Fortune Law (Commercial Solicitor), Paralegal – London

- Expanded my research abilities by working on different legal topics including banking, contract, and insolvency
- Improved attention to detail by drafting advice letters and emails to both clients and partners
- Enhanced my communication skills by taking calls from both existing and potential clients and log the enquiries onto our internal databases in a clear manner

### **EDUCATION**

Mar 2019 – June 2019	Flatiron School, London(UK) – In-person Software Engineering Bootcamp Languages and Frameworks include: JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, APIs, Capybara, RSpec, MVC design, REST architecture, Postgres, SQL, JSON, git, GitHub, CSS
Jan 2017 – Apr 2018	BPP Law School, London (UK) – Graduate Diploma in Law (GDL)
Nov 2009 – Oct 2015	S.U.N. University of Naples – Laurea Magistrale in Giurisprudenza (Integrated Master's Degree equivalent). Final grade 103/110

LANGUAGES: Italian (Native) | English (Advanced) | Spanish (Intermediate) | German (Basic)